Yasir Gaji



yasirgaji@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/yasirgaji



+234 908 300 4608



https://yasirgaji.netlify.app/

Summary

A Creative Front-end Developer | Entrepreneur | Physicist | Practising Essentialist | Fashion Enthusiast | Aspiring Javascript Engineer.

With 3+ years of Frontend Experience leveraging mark-up, Javascript with CMS to build responsive websites, softwares and interactive features that drive business growth and improve UX.

Experience

Product Manager

FAZSION

Jul 2020 - Present (9 months +)

Currently re-creating and crafting a scalable and robust application to help users make bulk orders at a blazing fast speed and best user experience.

Key Responsibilities:

- 1. Developing and overseeing growth strategies of the Fazsion B2B Sales Force.
- 2. Developing new business leads through digital marketing and telemarketing.
- 3. Proper management of products on the b2b ecommerce platform
- 4. Merchandising sales or increasing Fazsion brand presence.

Founder

Encode.

Nov 2019 - Nov 2020 (1 year 1 month)

Survival in today's digital world is very crucial and we at Encode are equipping kids and teens from the ages of 5 to 19 years old with technical skills which can be applied in their adolescent years at the work place.

TheYutes Frontend Web Developer

TheYutes

Jun 2019 - Nov 2020 (1 year 6 months)

Help build, develop, test, and debug responsive designs that would stand out not just only by the interface, but by the psychology, experience and professional coding indentation.

As the Front-end Developer working closely with the UI/UX team to translate design mock-ups into elegant, fast, responsive websites and web applications.

Principal duties and responsibilities are as follows - but not limited to:

- 1. Develop new user-facing features
- 2. Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- 3. Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs

- 4. Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability
- 5. Assure that all user input is validated before submitting to back-end
- 6. Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders
- 7. Maintain technical knowledge of web front-end industry standards, best practices and trends and evangelising these within the company.

borsko Frontend Developer

Bafsta Nigeria

Aug 2020 - Sep 2020 (2 months)

- Website revamping.
- High quality web designs.
- Payment Gateway setup.
- Developed high quality designs.

Web Developer

FAZSION

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020 (6 months)

Working at FAZSION I develop high quality web designs for their e-commerce site.

My focus is on user experience and back-end mostly for web and app. It is my job to make sure that the front-end is of a high standard and beautifully presented to each consumers needs.

Lead Developer

The Mindset Africa

Sep 2019 - Nov 2019 (3 months)

Contract project As the Front-end Developer working closely with the UI/UX team to translate design mock-ups into elegant, fast, responsive websites.

Principal duties and responsibilities are as follows - but not limited to:

- 1. Develop new user-facing features
- 2. Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- 3. Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs

Co Facilitator

wificombat

Oct 2018 - Jan 2019 (4 months)

Offer summer enrichment programs where students gain a sense of empowerment, independence and self-confidence as they learn to articulate their creativity in new ways by using technology.

Education



Lagos State University

Bachelor's degree, Physics 2019 - 2024

DOLPHIN SENIOR HIGH SCHOOL

2015 - 2018

Licenses & Certifications

DESIGN THEORY - Udemy

UC-BS5Q1PSB

Javascript Masterclass - Udemy

UC-4ab42df4-8278-4e11-b1ca-f2197a14f45d

Skills

SASS • JavaScript • HTML5 • Responsive Web Design • Web Design • User Interface Design • Wireframing • User Experience (UX) • Bootstrap • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)